-=昆明帝艺高清影音/200TB蓝光原盘服务/WD、ST全系列硬盘=-
片名: 卑鄙的我2
最高机密调查实验室 北极圈.
Huh?
嗯?
Three weeks, and we're still no closer to cracking this.
都已经三周了 我们还是毫无头绪
Right, bring him in!
好吧 把他叫来!
Yes, sir.
遵命 长官
艾格尼丝 生日快乐
This is the best party ever!
这是有史以来最棒的派对!
Yeah!
耶!
Ha!
哈!
Oh, no! A dragon is approaching!
不! 龙来了!
Fear not, for here come the gallant knights to save us.
不要怕 英勇的骑士来救我们了
Yay!
耶!
No, no, no. What do you mean she's not coming?
不 不 你说"她不能来"是什么意思?
I have a backyard full of these little girls
我家后院的小女孩们
who are counting on a visit from a fairy princess.
都在等着仙女姐姐的到来呢
Hurts! Stop it!
好疼! 停下!
Listen! I don't want a refund, I want the fairy princess, please!
听着! 我不要退款 我要仙女姐姐 求求你们了!
Please, I'm begging you.
求求你们了
You know what? I hope that you can sleep at night,
知道吗? 你破坏了小女孩们的愿望
you crusher of little girls' dreams!
你晚上都会睡不安稳的!
Ooh, ooh!
哦!
When's the fairy princess coming?
仙女姐姐什么时候来?
Any minute now!
她随时都可能出现!
Yay!
耶!
Stall them!
拖住她们!
魔术表演
Ooh!
哦!
Whoa! Whoa, okay! Okay, all right.
哇! 等一下! 好了
That's enough of the magic show.
魔术表演到此为止
Aw!
啊!
Wait, did you hear that?
等等 你们听到了吗?
It sounded like the twinkling sounds of magical fairy dust.
听起来像是魔法烟雾弥漫在空中
It's the fairy princess! She's coming!
是仙女姐姐来了!
Look!
看啊!
- Huh? Oh!  - Eh?
- 嗯? 哦!  - 嗯?
Ow!
啊!
Ow.
啊
It is I, Gruzinkerbell,
格鲁小叮当来了
the most magical fairy princess of all!
我可是最最厉害的仙女!
And I am here to wish Princess Agnes
我是来祝福艾格尼丝小公主
a very happy birthday!
生日快乐的!
How come you're so fat?
你为什么那么胖?
Because
因为
my house is made of candy,
我的房子是用糖果做的
and sometimes I eat instead of facing my problems!
有时候遇上了麻烦我就会不停地吃糖!
How come you have...
你为什么...
Okay, time for cake.
好了 该吃蛋糕了
Yay!
耶!
Thank you, Gruzinkerbell! You're the best fairy princess ever!
谢谢你 格鲁小叮当 你是最棒的仙女!
You are welcome, little girl!
不用谢 小姑娘!
I know it's really you, Gru. I'm just pretending for the other kids.
我知道是你 格鲁 我只是假装给其他小朋友看的
Hey there, Gru. Mr. Life of the Party!
你好啊 格鲁 你真是派对之王!
Hello, Jillian.
你好 吉莉安
So, I'm gonna go out on a limb here,
我想去钓那个帅哥
- but my friend Natalie is recently single, and...  - Oop.
- 不过我的朋友纳塔利可是单身已久 而且...  - 啊
No, no, no, get off the limb right now. No limb.
不 不 不 别钓帅哥 没帅哥
Come on, she's a riot!
别这样 她很狂野的!
She sings karaoke, she has a lot of free time,
她会唱卡拉OK 还有很多空闲时间
looks aren't that important to her...
她不在乎对方相貌...
No, Jills, that is not happening. Seriously, I'm fine.
不用 吉莉安 真的不用介绍了 真的 我这样挺好
Okay, fine, forget Natalie. How about my cousin Linda?
那好吧 不说纳塔利了 那我的表姐琳达怎么样?
No!
不用!
Oh! Oh! I know someone whose husband just died...
哦! 我还认识一个女人 她丈夫最近去世了...
I'm sorry, I did not see you there.
抱歉 没看到你站在那儿
Or there.
又没看到
不明物体
Kyle? Kyle?
凯尔? 你在哪?
Kyle, no! Do not do your business on the petunias!
凯尔 停! 不要在喇叭花丛里拉屎!
目标锁定
There you go. Those are Fred's, go crazy.
去弗雷德的花园 尽情释放吧
Good boy!
这才乖!
Mr. Gru?
格鲁先生吗?
I didn't... What? Yes?
我可没... 怎么了?
Hi! Agent Lucy Wilde of the AVL.
嗨! 我是反恶人联盟的露西・维尔德探员
Oh, whoops!
哦 拿反了!
Sorry, you're gonna have to come with me.
不好意思 你得跟我走一趟
Oh, sorry, I... freeze ray!
哦 抱歉 我... 冰冻射线!
You know, you really should announce
你应该先出招
your weapons after you fire them, Mr. Gru.
再喊招式的 格鲁先生
For example...
比如...
Lipstick taser!
口红镭射枪!
Oh, it works so good.
哦 太有效果了
Man!
天啊!
Large person.
猪一样重
Oh, sorry.
哦 抱歉
- Get in there...  - Huh?
- 给我进去...  - 嗯?
you big man!
你这个大块头!
Boss!
老大!
Uh? Huh!
嗯? 哦!
Whoa!
哇!
Huh?
嗯?
Ah! Whoo!
啊呜!
Ooh!
哦!
Oh!
啊!
Huh? Ah. Quack, quack!
嗯? 呱呱!
Wow!
哇!
What? Where?
这是哪里?
Whoa, foot is asleep.
啊 脚麻了
Ah, pins and needles!
啊 抓心挠肝啊!
Good afternoon, Mr. Gru.
下午好 古鲁先生
Eh.
嗯
I apologize for our methods in getting you here.
很抱歉用这种方式把你请来
I don't. I'd do it again in a heartbeat.
我可不抱歉 我巴不得再来一次
I am not gonna lie, I enjoyed that.
说实话 每一分每一秒都我都很享受
Every second of it. Gave me a bit of a buzz, actually.
事实上这让我心跳加速
That's enough, Agent Wilde.
够了 维尔德探员
Sorry, sir.
抱歉 长官
Okay, this is bogus!
这简直是胡闹!
I don't know who you people think you are, but...
我不知道你们觉得自己是干嘛的 但是...
We are the Anti-Villain League.
我们是反恶人联盟
An ultra-secret organization dedicated to fighting crime on a global scale.
一个致力于打击世界级犯罪的机密组织
Rob a bank, we're not interested. Kill someone, not our deal.
有人抢银行 我们不感兴趣 有人杀了人 我们可不愿意管
But you want to melt the polar ice caps, or vaporize Mount Fuji,
但如果你想融化北极冰盖 或者让富士山蒸发
or even steal the Moon...
还有偷走月亮...
Then we notice.
我们可就要管管了
First of all, you got no proof that I did that.
首先 你们没有证据那是我干的
Second, after I did do that, I put it back!
其次 我偷了月亮之后又把它还回去了!
We're well aware of that, Mr. Gru.
这我们都知道 格鲁先生
That's why we brought you here.
所以我们才找你来
I am the League's director, Silas Ramsbottom.
我是联盟的主席 赛拉斯・斯波顿
Bottom.
斯"屁股"
Hilarious.
真好笑
Agent Wilde?
维尔德探员?
Oh, me now? Ah.
该我了? 哦
Um, recently, an entire top-secret lab
最近 一个高级机密实验室
disappeared from the Arctic Circle.
从北极圈莫名消失了
Yeah, the entire lab, just...
整个实验室一下子...
gone. Where did it go?
消失了 他们去哪里了?
I don't care.
不关我的事
Hmm. The lab was devoted to experiments
嗯 这个实验室研究的
involving PX-41, a transmutation serum.
是一种变形血清 叫PX-41
What is PX-41, you ask? Mmm, it's pretty bad. Look.
你问PX-41是什么? 嗯 它可是极危险的 看吧
Ah!
啊!
Huh, you usually don't see that in bunnies.
哦 小兔子一般都不会这样
As you can see, in the wrong hands, the PX-41 serum
如你所见 PX-41血清如果落到坏人手里
could be the most devastating weapon on Earth.
它就会变成一种毁灭性的武器
Fortunately, it has a very distinct chemical footprint.
不过好在它的化学踪迹很特殊
And using the latest chem-tracking technology,
使用最新型的化学成分跟踪技术
we found traces of it in the Paradise Mall.
我们在天堂购物中心发现了它的踪迹
A mall?
购物中心?
Precisely. And we believe that one of these
是的 而且我们相信
shop owners is a master criminal.
商场里的某个店主就是犯罪分子
And that's where you come in.
你就要到那里
As an ex-villain, you know how a villain thinks, how a villain acts.
作为一个"前"恶人 你了解恶人的思想和行为
The plan is to set you up undercover
我们计划将你送入商场
at a shop in the mall, where hopefully we'll be able to...
当卧底 然后我们就能...
Okay, I see where this is going,
好了 我明白了
with all the Mission: Impossible stuff, but no. No!
你们说的是"碟中谍"里的那一套 但我不同意!
I'm a father now. And a legitimate businessman.
我是三个孩子的父亲 还是个遵纪守法的商人
I am developing a line of delicious jams and jellies.
我正在生产美味的果酱和果冻
"Jams and jellies"?
"果酱和果冻"?
Oh, attitude! That's right!
哦 怎么了! 就是果酱和果冻!
So, thanks, but no thanks.
好了 我不感兴趣
And here's a tip. Instead of tasing people and kidnapping them,
有个小建议 下次想要请人来能不能不要用电击 然后绑架来
maybe you should just give them a call!
你们可以给他打个电话!
Good day, Mr. Sheepsbutt.
过得愉快 羊屁股先生
Ramsbottom.
是斯波顿
Oh, yeah, like that's any better.
就像这样就好听了似的
Hello.
哈哈
Look, I probably shouldn't be saying this,
听着 也许我不该这么说
but your work as a villain was kind of amazing.
但是你恶人当得真是太好了
So, if you ever wanna get back to doing something awesome,
所以如果你想回来大干一番
give us a call.
给我们打电话
Hey, I told you guys to get to bed.
嘿 我都说了让你们先睡
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
So, when you going on your date?
你的约会怎么样?
What?
什么?
Remember, Miss Jillian said she was arranging a date for you.
不记得了吗 吉莉安小姐给你安排了一个相亲
Yeah, well, she is a nut job, and I'm not going on any date.
哦 她有点疯疯癫癫 我没去约会
Why not? Are you scared?
为什么? 你害怕了?
Hey, did you guys see the Moon Landing on TV?
嘿 你们看电视上的登月节目了吗?
Yeah, I can't believe it. It's so cool!
看了 真不敢相信 太酷了!
Excuse me? Lisa?
打扰一下? 丽莎?
I was talking to Billy the other day.
昨天我和比利聊天了
No way!
不可能!
He is so cute.
他好帅
Ah. Hey, Lisa, I was wondering if you...
嘿 丽莎 我想问你想不想...
Ew! Gru touched Lisa! Gru touched Lisa!
哦! 格鲁碰了丽莎! 格鲁碰了丽莎!
Ew!
哦!
Lisa's got Gruties!
丽莎被格鲁碰到了!
Scared? Of what? Women? No! That's bonkers!
害怕什么? 女人? 不! 太搞笑了!
I just have no interest in going on a date, that's all. Case closed.
我只是对约会不感兴趣 就这样 谈话结束
I'm not scared. Of women. Or dates.
我不害怕女人 也不怕约会
Let's go to bed.
睡觉了
Good night, Edith.
晚安 伊迪丝
Good night, Margo. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
晚安 玛尔戈 喔 喔 喔
Hold the horses. Who are you texting?
等一下 你在给谁发短信?
No one. Just my friend Avery.
没谁 就是一个朋友叫艾弗里
Avery. Avery? Is that a girl's name or a boy's name?
艾弗里? 男孩还是女孩?
Does it matter?
有关系吗?
No, no, it doesn't matter unless it's a boy!
不 没关系 除非是个小男孩!
I know what makes you a boy.
我知道你为什么是男的
Uh, ooh,
啊
you do?
是吗?
Your bald head.
因为你有光头
Oh, yes.
哦 是的
It's really smooth.
它很光滑
Sometimes I stare at it, and imagine a little chick popping out.
有时候我看着它 想象着有小鸡破壳而出
Peep peep peep.
叽叽叽
Good night, Agnes.
晚安 艾格尼丝
Never get older.
不要长大
果酱制作区
Hey, oh!
嘿 哦!
Uh...
嗯...
Okay, okay.
好的
Hey, Tim, nice haircut!
嘿 堤姆 发型不错!
Donnie, hang in there, baby! It's almost Friday.
唐尼 坚持就是胜利! 快到周五了
So, how's today's batch, Dr. Donnie?
今天的产量怎么样 唐尼博士?
I developed a new formula
我升级了配方
which allowed me to get every known
这样就能把所有莓子
kind of berry into one flavor of jelly.
混合成一种果冻
That tastes good!
太美味了!
I love the flavor of that!
我喜欢这口味!
It's horrible, isn't it?
很难吃 是吧?
No, no!
不!
Oh, we're making great progress!
我们已经有很大进步了!
Here, try some of this.
尝尝看
Mmm.
嗯
Ah.
啊
Whoa.
哇
Okay, just because everybody hates it, doesn't mean it's not good!
就算大家都不喜欢 也不太表它不好吃!
Listen, Gru.
听着 格鲁
There's something I've been meaning
有件事情
to talk to you about for some time now.
我早都想跟你说了
What? What's wrong?
什么事啊?
Um...
嗯...
I miss being evil.
我怀念作恶的日子
Sinister plots, large-scale crimes, it's what I live for.
那些阴谋诡计和犯罪计划 才是我人生的意义
I mean, don't you think there's more to our future than jelly?
那些才是我们的未来 而不是生产果冻 对吧?
Well, I'm also considering a line of jams.
我还打算生产果酱的
Um, the thing is, Gru,
嗯 是这样的 格鲁
I've had an offer of employment elsewhere.
别人向我伸出了橄榄枝
Dr. Nefario!
唐尼博士!
Come on, you're kidding, right?
别这样 你在开玩笑 是吧?
It's a great opportunity for me.
这对我来说是个好机会
Bigger lab, more evil,
更大的实验室 更坏的计划
full dental.
还有牙医
Very well.
好吧
Let us give you the proper send-off.
那让我们给你办一场像样的欢送会吧
Minions!
小伙伴们!
The highest honor awarded to Dr. Nefario
向唐尼博士致以最崇高的敬意
for your years of service,
感谢他多年来的奉献
the 21-fart gun salute!
放21次臭屁致敬!
Uh, I counted 22.
嗯 怎么多放了一次
Farewell, my friends.
再见了 朋友们
This may take a while.
还需要一段时间
Go about your business.
大家去干活吧
I miss you already!
我都开始想你们了!
Huh?
嗯?
Huh.
嗯
Are you sure we should be doing this?
我们真的要这么做?
Yes, it's for his own good.
是的 这是为他好
"开始约会吧"网站
Okay, we need to choose a picture.
我们得选一张照片
No.
不好
Scary.
吓人
Weird.
古怪
What is that?
怎么了?
Good morning, girls! I have an announcement to make.
早上好 姑娘们! 我有事情要宣布
Hey, what celebrity do you look like?
嘿 你看起来像那个明星?
Uh, Bruce Willis.
嗯 我像布鲁斯・威利斯("虎胆龙威"男主角)
Mmm, no.
才不像
Humpty Dumpty!
你像矮胖子!(童谣里的滑稽角色)
Ooh, Gollum!
他像咕噜!("指环王"里的怪物)
Okay, what are you doing?
好了 你们在干嘛?
We're signing you up for online dating!
我们在给你注册交友网站!
Oh, okay. What? No, no, no.
哦 好吧 什么? 不 不
Oh, come on. It's fun.
别这样 会很好玩的
And it's time for you to get out there.
你也该找个对象了
No! Stop! No one is ever getting out there! Ever!
不! 没人需要找对象! 没人!
Oh! Okay, now for the announcement.
好了! 我要宣布我的事情了
I have accepted a new job.
我找了份新工作
Whoa! Really?
哇! 真的吗?
Yes, I have been recruited by a top-secret agency
嗯 一家秘密机构聘请我
to go undercover and save the world!
去当卧底拯救世界!
You're gonna be a spy?
你要当间谍?
That's right, baby!
当然了 宝贝!
Gru's back in the game.
格鲁要东山再起啦
With gadgets and weapons and cool cars. The whole deal.
跑车 手枪 还有全套装备
Awesome!
太棒了!
Are you really gonna save the world?
你真的会拯救世界吗?
Yes. Yes, I am.
是的 我会的
Ah!
啊!
Hmm.
嗯
"Bake My Day."
"烘焙时光"
Blech.
唉
All right, here is the cupcake recipe I got off the Internet.
好了 这是我在网上找的蛋糕食谱
And don't go nuts with the sprinkles!
别把巧克力屑弄洒了!
Whoo.
啊
I wasn't expecting that. Or was I?
我没想到会这样 对吧?
Ooh. You got... you got a little...
哦 你有点... 有点...
Here, I'll get it.
我来帮你擦
Oh.
哦
It's just spreading.
好像越抹越多啊
All right, all right. I got it! Stop it!
好了 我自己来! 住手!
Oh.
哦
I'll let you get it.
那还是你自己来吧
Yeah, what you just saw there was a little
嗯 你刚刚看到的那些
something new I've been working on.
都是我新发明的招数
It's a combination of Jujitsu, Krav Maga, Aztec warfare
它融合了柔术 近身格斗 阿芝特克武术
and krumping.
和小丑舞蹈的精华
Okay, that's weird. Why are you here?
但是这很奇怪 你怎么会在这里?
On assignment from Silas. I'm your new partner.
赛拉斯派我来的 我是你的新搭档
Yay!
耶!
What? No, no "yay".
什么? "耶"什么"耶"
Ramsbottom didn't say anything about a partner.
羊屁股先生可没告诉我还有搭档
Well, it seems that because of your checkered past,
可能是因为你有案底的原因
everyone else refused to work with you.
所以别人都不愿意和你合作
But not me. I stepped up.
于是我毛遂自荐了
And I'm new, so I kind of have to do what they tell me anyway.
我是新手 所以其实你可以指挥我
Walla!
你好!
Ya!
呀!
Aah!
啊!
Do you know this guy?
你认识他吗?
Yes, he's one of my minions.
是的 他是我的手下
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦 抱歉
I should have known.
失礼了
You are free to go.
你可以走了
Uh? Ah!
嗯? 啊!
Kampai!
干杯!
Oh!
哦!
Dave...
戴夫啊...
Earth to Dave!
呼叫戴夫!
Huh?
嗯?
You can leave now.
你该走了
Oh, uh...
哦...
So, what do we got? Who's on the list?
什么情况? 名单上都有谁?
Fire them at me.
读给我听
First suspect, Hedda Blumentoft,
第一位嫌疑人是海达・布朗托夫特
proprietor of Mum's the Word Floral Shop.
"妈咪世界"鲜花店的老板
No, not her.
不是她
Okay, moving on...
好吧 那下一个...
Chuck Kinney, owner of Stuff-A-Bear.
"填充熊宝宝"商店的店主查德・肯尼
Ooh.
哦
I don't think so.
他也不是
Hello?
有人吗?
Buenos días, my friends!
早上好 朋友们!
I am Eduardo Perez,
我是爱德华多・佩雷斯
owner of Salsay Salsa restaurant, across the mall.
是对面莎莎舞餐厅的老板
Now open for breakfast. And you are?
现在我们还供应早餐 你是?
Gru. And this is Lucy. And we are closed.
我是格鲁 她是露西 但是我们还没开门
This is just going to take un momento.
一会会就好
I am throwing a big Cinco de Mayo party,
我要举办一场盛大的"五月五日节"派对(墨西哥的一个节日)
and I am going to need 200 of your best cupcakes
我要订200个你们这最好的小蛋糕
decorated with the Mexican flag.
上面插上墨西哥小旗
It looks something like this.
看起来就和这个差不多
What do you think?
怎么样?
- Ooh.  - Oh.
- 哦  - 哦
Look away!
不要看他!
You, whoo.
哇 哇
Anyway, I have to go. It's all settled. I'll pick them up next week!
好了 我得走了 就这么说好了 我下周来取蛋糕!
Have a good day. Come by if you get a chance, okay?
祝你们愉快 有空过来玩 好吧?
And welcome to the mall family.
欢迎加入商场大家庭
El Macho.
他是埃尔马乔
What?
什么?
But it couldn't be.
不可能啊
What? What couldn't be?
什么不可能?
That guy looks exactly like a villain named El Macho.
那个人很像一个叫埃尔马乔的恶棍
From about 20 years ago.
那还是20年前的事
He was ruthless!
他心狠手辣!
He was dangerous.
十分危险
And as the name implies, very macho.
他就像他的名字一样 非常霸道
He had a reputation for pulling off heists using only his bare hands!
他因为赤手空拳去打劫而出名
But sadly, like all the greats, El Macho was gone too soon.
但就像所有英雄的悲剧 埃尔马乔传奇很快就陨落了
He died in the most macho way possible.
他死的方式也是最霸气的
Riding a shark
他骑着鲨鱼
with 250 pounds of dynamite strapped to his chest
胸前绑着250磅的炸药
into the mouth of an active volcano!
冲到了爆发的火山口!
It was glorious.
真是惊心动魄
Yeah, sounds like El Macho's pretty dead.
嗯 听起来埃尔马乔肯定是死了
They never found the body. Oh, no.
他的尸体一直没有被发现 一直也没
All that was ever retrieved was a pile of singed chest hair.
只找到了一撮烧焦了的胸毛
But that face! It has got to be El Macho!
那张脸! 他肯定是埃尔马乔!
Then what do you say you and I break into his restaurant? Tonight?
那我们偷偷溜进他的餐厅怎么样? 今晚就去?
Yes, that's good, because I am telling you,
嗯 好的 因为如果这里
if anybody in this place has the PX-41 serum,
有个人有PX-41血清
it's him.
那肯定是他
All right, all right, homework done, pajamas on, teeth brushed, time for bed.
好了 做完作业 穿上睡衣 刷好牙 该睡觉啦
What's the big hurry?
着什么急啊?
I just have a lot of work to do.
我还有很多工作要做
Work, what kind of work?
工作 什么工作?
Very important business.
非常重要的工作
So, hugs, kisses.
抱一抱 亲一亲
Good night, sleep tight, don't let the bedbugs blah-blah-blah.
晚安 好梦 别让那些啥啥啥打扰了你们的梦乡
Whoa!
啊!
But you said you'd help me practice
但是你答应过我
my part for the Mother's Day show.
帮我练习母亲节表演的
Fine, fine. Let me hear it. Quickly.
好吧 让我听听 抓紧时间
She kisses my boo-boos, she braids my hair.
她亲吻我的小伤口 她给我梳辫子
My mother is beyond compare.
我的母亲是无与伦比的
We love you, mothers, everywhere.
我们爱你到永远
Wow! That was something else.
啊! 这真是很奇特的表演
I really liked the way you smiled at the end.
我很喜欢你结尾的微笑
Let's try this one more time,
我们再来一遍
but a teensy bit less like a zombie, okay?
这次别模仿僵尸了 好吗?
Okay.
好吧
She kisses my boo-boos, she braids my hair...
她亲吻我的小伤口 她给我梳辫子...
Perfect! Time to go.
完美! 该睡觉了
I don't think I should do this.
我觉得我不应该去表演
Well, what do you mean? Why not?
怎么了? 为什么不去?
I don't even have a mom.
我都没有妈妈
Well, you don't need one to do the show.
表演节目不一定必须真的有妈妈
I mean, you did the Veterans Day Pageant
就像你在退伍军人联欢会上表演
and you haven't been in combat.
也不用非要打过仗啊
This is different.
这是两码事
Okay, well, then maybe you can just use your imagination.
好吧 那你可以发挥一下你的想象力
You mean I pretend I have a mom?
你是说要我假装我有妈妈?
Yes, right? You can do that, can't you?
嗯 对吧? 这样就可以了 是吧?
Yeah! I do that all the time.
是的! 我一直都是这样
Thanks, Gru!
谢谢了 格鲁!
Hey!
嘿!
All right. Hey, hey, no, no! No.
好了 嘿 停 停!
Hey. Hey, please.
嘿 停一下
Kevin, Jerry, watch the girls for me, okay?
凯文和杰里 去照顾小女孩们 明白吗?
Dave, Stuart, come this way! With me! Come on!
戴夫和图尔特 跟我来! 这边走!
Come on!
走了!
Mmm-mmm!
嗯嗯!
Oh!
哦!
Mmm-hmm.
嗯
Huh?
嗯?
- Oca!  - Oca!
- 别怕!  - 不怕!
Looka too!
看你吓的!
Huh?
嗯?
莎莎舞餐厅
We're stealth ninjas. We make no sound.
我们是忍者 悄无声息
Right. Gotcha.
好的 明白
Ya!
呀!
All right, El Macho. You're going down.
来吧 埃尔马乔 你要倒霉了
- Wait! Wait.  - What?
- 等一下!  - 怎么了?
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
I'm checking for laser beam alarm triggers.
我在检查这里有没有激光警报装置
It's a restaurant!
这是家餐厅!
You never know what kind of booby traps
永远都被能对陷阱
this guy could have set. Huh? Come on.
掉以轻心 嗯? 对吧
There are no booby traps.
这里没有陷阱
Ha! Booby!
哈! 说中了吧!
Oh. There's a chicken.
哦 是一只鸡
Are you lost, little guy?
你迷路了吗 小兄弟?
You must be lost.
你肯定是迷路了
Ha! Some guard dog.
哈! 这就是他的看门狗
Get it off of me! Get it off of me!
帮我把它赶走! 帮我把它赶走!
Aah!
啊!
I got you!
抓到你了!
I got it!
我来了!
Ha!
哈!
Oh!
哦!
What is wrong with that chicken?
这只鸡怎么回事?
Hey, that pollo is loco.
嘿 这鸡仔是疯子
No?
不是吗?
Okay, let's go.
好了 我们走
Are you getting anything?
你发现什么了吗?
No, not yet.
还没有
But, hey, maybe you can find something with these X-ray goggles.
但是你用这个X光护目镜可能会发现点什么
Bah.
唉
How are they working? Tell me! Tell me!
护目镜怎么样? 快说说!
Aah! Oof!
啊! 哇!
What's wrong? Is something wrong?
怎么了? 有事吗?
That's an image I'll never get out of my brain. Blech!
那画面真是灼伤我双眸啊!
I knew it!
我就知道!
The serum is in here!
血清在里面!
Ooh, then let's get it.
哦 那我们快拿走它
This is going to be good!
终于要成功了!
Ah.
啊
Ah-ha!
啊哈!
What?
什么?
辣酱
Salsa?
辣酱?
Aw, man.
怎么这样
Oh.
哦
Somebody's going to die tonight.
今晚有人将死
Pollito!
波立特啊!
What did they do to you? Pollito? Can you hear me?
他们对你做了什么? 波立特 你没事吧?
Who would do this to such a sweet little chicken?
谁会对可爱的小鸡下此狠手?
What? Who's there?
怎么? 谁在那里?
Mmm-mmm.
哦哦
You coming out? Or am I gonna go in?
你自己出来? 还是我进去抓你?
Yah!
呀!
Huh?
嗯?
Stop!
别跑!
My eyes!
我的眼睛!
Gru, call one of your munchkins!
格鲁 赶紧呼叫你的小伙伴们!
We've been spotted! Come get us!
我们被发现了! 快来接我们!
Huh? Hey!
嗯? 嘿!
Ah!
啊!
Hmm, subtle.
车技真不错
Over here! Over here!
在这边! 这边!
Over...
在...
here.
这边
Hold tight!
抓住了!
Aah!
啊!
I have you now!
抓到你们了!
Yay! Ice cream!
耶! 卖冰淇淋的!
Huh?
嗯?
All right, there he is.
好了 他来了
Suspect number eight, Floyd Eaglesan.
八号嫌疑人弗洛伊德・依格桑
Oh, okay.
哦 好吧
See if you can get closer. Go, go.
你能不能去近一点 走吧
All right.
好了
What the...
这是...
警告:巨烫无比!
Oh, no. That's not good.
哦 不 糟了
Whoa!
啊!
Hey, uh, what?
嘿 怎么回事?
Oh!
哦!
Hey, Gru!
嘿 格鲁!
Oh, girls! What are you doing here?
哦 姑娘们! 你们在这里干什么?
Well, we thought we'd come visit you at work.
我们想去看看你工作
So, you're saving the world in a garbage can?
你躲在垃圾桶里拯救世界?
Funny.
太逗了
Hey! There you are.
嘿! 你在这儿
Oh. Who's this?
哦 她们是谁?
Lucy, these are my girls, Margo, Edith and Agnes.
露西 这是我的女儿们 玛尔戈 伊迪丝和艾格尼丝
Girls, Lucy. Lucy, girls.
姑娘们 这是露西 这是我的女儿
- Hello.  - Hi.
- 你好  - 嗨
Are you single?
你结婚了吗?
Oh! Goodness.
哦! 天啊
Oh, hey! I have an idea. Since Lucy and I have lots of work to do,
嘿! 我有个主意 既然我和露西还有很多工作要做
- why don't you girls go and explore the mall?  - Bye!
- 你们去商场里逛一逛怎么样?  - 拜!
Here is some money, go buy some useless mall junk.
给你们点钱 去买点那些没用的玩意儿吧
Some headbands and...
发带什么的...
Are you gonna marry Lucy?
你会和露西结婚吗?
Are you out of your gourd? No! She just works with me.
你疯了吗? 不会! 她只是和我一块工作
Plus, you love her.
但是你爱她啊
You love her! You love her! You really, really love her!
你爱她! 你爱她! 你就是就是很爱她!
And you're gonna get married!
你们会结婚的!
Okay, stop. This is a song of lies.
停 这首歌是骗人的
And I will be the flower girl!
我会是婚礼上的小天使!
I don't even like her. Now, go have fun!
我根本不喜欢她 快去玩吧!
Almost forgot. Hugs!
差点忘了 抱一个!
Good luck saving the world. Bye.
好好拯救世界吧 拜
Bye, Gru!
拜 格鲁!
Kids, right? They're funny.
小孩子就这样嘛 她们多有趣
Those girls totally adore you.
你的女儿们真的很喜欢你
I bet you're a fun dad.
你一定是个好爸爸
Huh.
哈
I am pretty fun.
我是个好爸爸
Is that stealing?
你这算是偷吗?
Not if my wish was that I would get a lot of free coins.
我许的愿望就是得到很多硬币 所以这不算是偷
Whoa!
啊!
Cool glasses.
眼镜很酷
Oh.
哦
I'm Antonio.
我叫安东尼奥
I'm Margo.
我叫玛尔戈
I was just going to get a cookie. Care to join me?
我正想去吃块饼干 要不要一起来?
Uh, sure.
好的
I'm Margo.
我叫玛尔戈
Um, I'll catch up with you guys later.
我一会儿跟你们汇合
Bye!
拜!
Can I be the first to say, "Ew!"
我能第一个说"恶心"吗
We gotta go tell Gru!
我们得告诉格鲁!
鹰发俱乐部
All right, I'm going in.
好了 我进去了
If it picks up any traces of the serum, the sensor in your belt buckle
一旦感应到血清的痕迹 你皮带扣里的感应器
will make a sound like this...
就会发出这样的声音...
Mee-maw! Mee-maw!
咪喵! 咪喵!
- Mee-maw! Mee-maw!  - Okay!
- 咪喵! 咪喵!  - 好了!
I get it. I get it.
知道了 知道了
Welcome to Eagle Hair Club.
欢迎来到鹰发俱乐部
It's about time you showed up,
你是该出现了
Mr. Gru.
格鲁先生
You know my name?
你知道我的名字?
When someone moves into the mall who is folically-challenged,
当没头发的人进入中心时
I make it my business to know all about them.
我的任务就是彻底了解他们
You are bald, and that is bad.
你是秃头 很容易暴露你
There you go, my sweet.
给你戴上 亲爱的
I'm getting nothing so far.
目前没反应
I think you need to move around.
你可能得四处转转
Wow, this looks interesting. What is it?
哇哦 这个看起来很有趣 这是什么?
I take it you're an art lover?
你是艺术爱好者吗?
No serum.
没有血清
Yeah, not so much.
不算是吧
Oh, how about this impressive trinket?
这个造型独特的小玩意怎么样呢?
I'd hardly call it a trinket, Mr. Gru.
我从不叫它小玩意 格鲁先生
- Nothing.  - The International...
- 没反应  - 国际上...
Yeah, I don't care.
我不感兴趣
Mee-maw! Mee-maw!
咪喵! 咪喵!
Hold on, I'm picking up something. Behind that wall!
慢着 感应到东西了 在墙后面!
Ah, and what do we have here?
啊 这里有什么?
These are my trial wigs. You should take one.
这些是我的假发样品 你应该买一个
No, thanks. So, what's on the other side of the wall?
不用了 话说墙的另一边有什么?
Here you are! Look at me! Focus!
喂! 看着我! 专心点!
Gru?
怎么了格鲁?
I promise that this wig will transform you from ugly
我保证这顶假发会让你从奇丑无比
to irresistible.
变得魅力撩人
Margo has a boyfriend!
玛尔戈有男朋友了!
And they're going on a date!
而且他们约会去了!
Date? Boyfriend?
约会? 男朋友?
What?
什么情况?
There she goes!
她在那!
Oh, you're so funny.
哦 你真是太幽默了
Gross!
好恶心!
- Look, they're in love.  - Oh, no, no, no.
- 快看 他们恋爱了  - 不不不
Do not say that. No, no, no.
别这么说 不不 不会的
And my dream is to one day play video games for a living.
我的梦想是将来以打电子游戏为生
Wow.
哇哦
You're so complicated.
你真是太有内涵了
Margo.
玛尔戈啊
What is going on here?
这怎么回事?
Oh, Gru, se llama Antonio. Me llamo Margo.
格鲁 他叫安东尼奥 我的名字是玛尔戈
Me llama-lama ding-dong. Who cares? Let's go.
我叫羊驼喇嘛叮叮叮 管他呢? 我们走
Whoa!
哇哦!
Kids eat free on Tuesdays.
周二儿童免费
Yay, Pop!
好 棒极了!
That's awesome!
太炫了!
- So good to see you again, mi compadre!  - Ha! Yeah.
- 很高兴再见面 我的朋友!  - 哈! 呵呵
Oh, I see you have already met my father.
看来你已经认识我父亲了
What? Father?
什么? 父亲?
Si. Look at this crazy small world we live in, eh?
对啊 看我们的世界是多么小啊?
Come, sit, let me get you something.
来 坐 我给你上点吃的
- Oh, look at you.  - Heh?
- 哦 小公鸡  - 怎么样?
He likes me.
他喜欢我
Oh, oh! I'm sorry. Pollito is usually very friendly.
哦! 抱歉 波立特通常不啄人
He had a rough night.
他昨晚过得不好
Well, we really should be going. Girls, come on.
我们该走了 姑娘们 快点
That is a pity.
太可惜了
Young love is beautiful, no?
年轻的爱是美丽的 不是吗?
No!
不是!
You know, they're not in love. They hardly know each other.
我是说 他们没恋爱 他们几乎不认识
You are right, Cabeza de huevo.
你说的没错 蛋头
They must get to know each other better!
他们必须进一步认识对方
Antonio, why don't you invite your girlfriend and her family
安东尼奥 为什么不邀请你的女朋友和她家人
to our Cinco de Mayo party?
来我们的五月五日节派对呢?
No, no.
不用了
Si!
好哎!
I'm sorry, El Macho?
什么 埃尔马乔?
Hadn't we eliminated him as a suspect
我们不是在莎莎舞事件后
after the whole salsa incident?
就已经排除他的嫌疑了吗?
Yes, but there has been a new development,
是 但有新进展
and I'm telling you, this is the guy.
我可以保证 他就是我们找的人
You need to arrest him immediately.
你必须马上逮捕他
And his deviously charming son!
还有他那不安好心的迷人儿子!
I'm pretty sure that the son is involved, too.
我非常确定他儿子也参与了
The son, also! You got to get the son!
儿子 也参与了! 你必须抓住儿子!
I think that the son is the mastermind!
我认为儿子才是主谋!
There's a look, there's a devilish look
那个眼神 他眼睛里
in his eyes, and I don't like it!
那邪恶的神情 我不喜欢!
Yes, but I don't really see any evidence.
好吧 但我没看到任何证据
Evidence, schmevidence. I go with my gut,
证据啥的都是浮云 我相信我的直觉
and my gut tells me that this guy is El Macho.
而我的直觉告诉我那个人就是埃尔马乔
Lock him up, lock up the son.
把他铐起来 还有他儿子
Don't forget about the son. The kid gives me the creeps!
千万别漏了儿子 那孩子让我毛骨悚然!
Oh, dear, dear, dear.
哦 天啊 天啊
But, on the less crazy side of things,
但是 说起不太疯狂的事
Gru discovered traces of the serum at Eagle Hair Club!
格鲁在鹰发俱乐部发现了血清痕迹!
Hmm, interesting.
有意思
Yeah! And you know who made that happen? Huh?
是啊! 你知道这是谁的功劳吗? 哈?
This guy. Nailed it. Amazing, right?
这个家伙 搞定了 很厉害吧?
No, I mean, sure. But it's not him, it is El Macho!
不 我是说 当然 但不是他 是埃尔马乔!
Mr. Gru, please!
格鲁先生 拜托!
No! It is him, and I will prove it!
不! 就是他 我会证明的!
Gru, come on!
格鲁 别这样!
He really thinks it's El Macho.
他真的认为是埃尔马乔
Can you tell?
你觉得呢?
Oh. Whoo!
哦 嗨!
Give me that!
给我!
坏蛋网
连接中断
Kevin, the Wi-Fi's out!
凯文 无线网断了!
Kevin?
凯文呢?
Hey, Lance, where the heck is Kevin?
兰斯 你知道凯文去哪了?
All right, we need to revisit the number of vacation days you guys get.
好了 我们得重新制定你们假期天数了
I can't find anybody anymore.
叫谁也找不到
Gru, it's Jillian!
格鲁 我是吉莉安!
I've got good news!
好消息!
I have my friend Shannon here with me.
我朋友莎伦和我一起来了
I was thinking you two could get some grub.
我想你们可以一起吃个饭
You know, tear it up, see what happens!
打破常规 顺其自然!
Open up!
开门!
La, la, la, la, la, la, la...
啦啦啦啦啦...
Agnes! Agnes, tell Jillian I'm not here.
艾格尼丝! 艾格尼丝 告诉吉莉安我不在
Gru's not here.
格鲁不在
Are you sure?
你确定?
Yes, he just told me!
对 他刚告诉我的!
Mmm-mmm!
嗯哼!
I mean, no, he didn't just tell me.
我是说 他没告诉我
Agnes, where is Gru?
艾格尼丝 格鲁在哪?
He's putting on lipstick!
涂口红呢!
He's swatting at flies!
拍苍蝇呢!
No! No!
不对! 不对!
He's chopping his head off!
他砍自己的脑袋呢!
He's pooping?
他在拉便便?
I know you're in there, Gru!
我知道你在里面 格鲁!
There's no way you're getting out of this!
这次你别想逃掉!
I have to tell you, I was so nervous about tonight.
我必须告诉你 我今晚非常紧张
I mean there's just so many phonies out there!
我是说这年头骗子真是太多了!
Yes, I hear you.
嗯 我懂你
Oh, so, do you work out?
那么 你健身吗?
Well...
这个...
I mean, obviously, you don't, but would you consider it?
我是说 很显然你没有 但你会考虑吗?
Huh? Physical fitness is very important to Shannon.
啊? 身体健康对莎伦来说非常重要
As you can tell, right? Huh?
你看得出来 对吧? 啊?
Ah.
哈
I can tell.
现在看出来了
Solid.
结实
We are in the restaurant, you know.
我们可是在餐馆呢
- Hi.  - Takeout for Lucy?
- 嗨  - 露西的外卖?
Sure, just a sec.
好的 稍等
Your accent is so exotic.
你的口音太有异国风情了
Ah. Well, thank you very much.
啊 谢谢夸奖
I know someone who can fix that for you.
我认识熟人能给你治好
And you'll be talking normal in no time!
你立马就能正常说话了!
Whoo. Is it hot in here?
呜 这里很热吗?
How's the food?
东西好吃吗?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Are you wearing a wig?
慢着 慢着 你戴着假发吗?
What?
什么?
Ah! I don't think so.
啊! 没有啊
I knew it.
我就知道
You're a phony. I hate phonies!
你是个骗子 我恨骗子!
Oh, what? No. These locks are all mine.
什么? 不 这些头发都是我的
No, they're not!
它们不是!
You know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna rip that thing off your head,
你知道我要干嘛吗? 我要把那玩意从你头上扯下来
and show everyone what a bald-headed phony you are.
让大家都知道你是个秃头的骗子
I don't think so, Miss Lady.
不可能的 小姐
Hello?
喂?
Hello? Are you...
喂? 你...
Hey, Gru.
嘿 格鲁
Hello, Lucy. How are you doing?
你好 露西 怎么样啊?
Wow, looks like your date's out for the count.
看来你的约会对象晕过去了
It's like she's been shot with a mild moose tranquilizer.
貌似是被温和的驼鹿镇定剂射中了
Yeah, I'm winking because that's what actually happened.
我眨眼是因为确实如此
Scusi, what's happening here? She no like?
对不起 发生什么事了? 她不喜欢吗?
Oh, she's just, uh...
她只是 呃...
Oh, ho.
哦 呵呵
Sì, Sì. Sì.
懂了 懂了
Shall we take her home?
要把她弄回家吗?
Oh!
哦!
Well, I think you did it. You just officially had the worst date ever.
好吧 你做到了 你刚正式经历了史上最差的约会
Huh, tell me about it.
哈 可不是嘛
Don't worry. It can only get better from here, right?
别担心 从此只会走上坡了 对吧?
But if it doesn't, you can always borrow my dart gun.
如果不是的话 随时可以借我的镖枪
I've had to use it on one or two dates myself.
我自己约会的时候也用过一两次
Yeah, you know, as far as dates go,
这个嘛 约会这种事
I think I'm good with just the one.
我想这一次就够了
Well, good night, partner.
那晚安了 伙伴
This was fun.
今晚非常有趣
Yes. Surprisingly, it was.
是啊 出人意料的确实如此
Oh, and, uh, just between you and me?
还有 我们之间的秘密?
You look much better bald.
你还是秃头好看一些
See you tomorrow.
明天见
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
呱 呱 呱 呱 呱!
Yay!
耶!
So, I take it the date went well?
看来约会非常顺利?
No, it was horrible.
不 糟糕至极
High-five!
击掌!
Bump it.
碰屁股
Mr. Ramsbottom?
斯波顿先生?
Oh, hello.
你好
What are you doing here?
你们在干嘛?
- We got him.  - Got who?
- 我们抓到他了  - 谁啊?
Floyd Eaglesan!
是弗洛伊德・依格桑干的!
Our agents located a secret room in his shop last night
我们的探员昨晚在他店里找到一间密室
and discovered this.
然后发现了这个
It's empty, but we found traces of the PX-41 serum in it.
是空的 但我们发现了PX-41血清的痕迹
He's our man.
他就是我们要找的人
So, somehow, in spite of your incompetence, we solved this one.
不论如何 尽管你不称职 我们解决问题了
I was framed!
我是被陷害的!
You won't get away with this!
你们不会有好下场的!
Get your mitts off of me! I am a legitimate businessman.
把手放开! 我可是合法商人
Ah. All right. So what now?
好吧 现在呢?
Well, now you're free to go back to your business.
现在你可以继续你的生意了
Mmm. Jams and jellies.
嗯 果酱和果冻
And it looks like Agent Wilde will be
而维尔德探员会被派到
transferring to our Australian branch.
我们的澳大利亚分局
Australia?
澳大利亚?
Yes.
是的
But thank you for everything.
但谢谢你所做的
And by everything, of course I mean nothing.
而你所做的 当然是无所作为
Toodle pip and cheerio, Mr. Gru.
再见冤家 加油了 格鲁先生
- Hey, there.  - Hey.
- 你好啊  - 嘿
So, we got him.
我们抓到他了
Yay. That's great.
是啊 太棒了
And now you're going to Australia?
现在你要去澳大利亚了?
Well, it's not definite yet. I'm still figuring it out.
还没最终确定 我仍然在考虑
I've already been working on my accent.
不过我已经在练习口音了
Wallaby. Didgeridoo.
小袋鼠 迪吉里杜管(澳大利亚土著使用的一种乐器)
Hugh Jackman.
休・杰克曼(澳大利亚男影星)
So, um... pretty excited.
所以 呃... 蛮兴奋的
Great.
那就好
Well, good luck.
那祝你好运
Thanks. You, too.
谢谢 你也是
Oh! Here. I wanted to give you this.
哦! 我想把这个给你
Your lipstick taser?
你的口红镭射枪?
Yeah, it's just a memento.
嗯 当作纪念吧
Just, you know, from the first time we met.
从我们第一次见面到现在
Oh. Thank you, Lucy.
谢谢 露西
Agent Wilde.
维尔德探员
Well, it looks like they need you, so...
他们好像需要你 所以...
Yeah, I better go.
是啊 我最好过去了
Bye, Gru.
再见 格鲁
I brought you an umbrella.
我给你带伞来了
Ah, thank you.
啊 谢谢
What are you doing out here?
你在外面做什么?
Remember when you said that I liked Lucy?
记得你说我喜欢露西吗?
Well, it turns out,
最后我才意识到
you're right.
你说对了
Really?
真的?
Yes, but...
对 但是...
Well, she's moving away.
她要走了
I'm never going to see her again.
我再也见不到她了
Is there anything I could do to help?
有什么我能做的吗?
Aw, I don't... I don't think so, sweetheart.
噢 我... 我觉得没有 亲爱的
Well, is there anything you could do?
那有什么你能做的吗?
Hello, Lucy. This is Gru.
你好 露西 我是格鲁
I know up to this point our relationship
我知道到目前为止我们的关系
has been strictly professional,
都是严格的工作需求
and you're leaving for Australia and all, but...
而你要去澳大利亚了 但是...
Okay, here is the question.
好吧 我想问你
Would you like to...
你愿意...
to go out on a date?
和我约会吗?
Uh, no.
呃 不愿意
Okay, that's not helping.
你这是在帮倒忙
All right, here we go. For real this time.
好了 开始了 这次是真的
I can do this.
我可以的
Agh! I hate you!
啊! 我恨你!
Ah.
啊
火警
Eh.
也不错
- Kevin?  - Mmm?
- 凯文?  - 嗯?
Tom?
汤姆吗?
Hello!
你好啊!
- Kampai!  - Kampai!
- 干杯!  - 干杯!
Huh? Kampai!
啊? 干杯!
Cinco de May-ya-yo! Cinco de May-ya-yo!
五月五日节! 五月五日节!
This place is awesome!
这儿好棒!
Okay. Let's party, huh?
好了 开始狂欢吧?
But first, let's go over the rules.
不过首先 咱得再重申下规矩
Because what is fun without the rules?
没规矩 怎么有乐子呢 对吧?
Agnes, easy on the churros.
艾格尼丝 油条悠着点儿吃
- Edith, try not to kill anyone.  - Hai!
- 伊迪丝 不要伤到别人  - 好!
Margo!
还有玛尔戈!
Hello, Mr. Gru.
你好呀 格鲁先生
Okay.
好了
Gru!
喂 格鲁!
There must be the standard 6 feet of space between you and boys.
你必须和男生保持6英尺的距离
Especially this boy.
特别是这位
Ah, you are a funny man.
您真有趣
There are no rules, se?or. It's Cinco de Mayo.
长官 这儿可没什么规矩 今天是五月五日节嘛
Come on! They're starting the dance!
来吧! 要开始跳舞了!
Arriba!
好耶!
So glad you could make it, mi compadre.
朋友 您愿意来 我真高兴
Hey, what's wrong?
嘿 怎么了?
Oh, nothing. Nothing is wrong.
没什么 什么事都没有
I'm just chilling with the guac, from my chip hat.
我只是在品味饼干帽里的鳄梨酱
Gru, please. I know that look all too well.
拜托 格鲁 这种表情我太熟悉了
It is the look of a broken heart.
这是心碎的表情
How did you know?
你怎么知道?
Believe me, my friend, I too have spent many nights
朋友 相信我吧 我也曾夜夜无眠
trying to drown my sorrows in guacamole.
将自己的伤心事深埋在鳄梨酱中
- You?  - Yes.
- 你?  - 当然
But we are survivors.
不过我们都是过来人
There's much more to us than meets the eye.
咱们都是有故事的人呐
Enjoy the party.
玩得开心
Say what?
什么?
Would you like some peanuts or pretzels?
您想要花生还是脆饼?
That's a good joke.
真好笑
I just did a boom boom.
我刚便便过
I really need you to make a choice, hon.
小姐 请快选一样吧
I choose Gru.
我选格鲁
I choose Gru!
我选格鲁!
Thank you, Gru stewardess!
谢谢你 空姐格鲁!
You're welcome!
别客气!
You have not lost your touch, my friend.
宝刀未老呀 朋友
Ah-ha! I knew it!
啊哈! 我就知道!
You are El Macho!
你是埃尔马乔!
That's right!
没错!
Nobody believed me!
没人相信我!
Ho-ho! But I knew you weren't dead!
吼吼! 但我知道 你没死
Of course not. I merely faked my death.
当然啦 那只是我假死
But now, it's time for me
但是现在 我要
to make a spectacular return to evil.
高调回归坏人界了
Doctor, I think it's time we showed Gru what we're up to here.
博士 该给格鲁展示下我们现在的工作了
Dr. Nefario?
尼法里奥博士?
Nice to see you, Gru.
格鲁 很高兴见到你
Wha...?
什么...?
So, this is your new job opportunity?
这就是你的新工作?
Absolutely. You're gonna like this.
没错 你一定会喜欢这个
Sorry.
抱歉
I had to borrow some of your minions, but it was for a worthy cause.
我迫不得已借了你几个仆从 不过绝对很值当
Oh! Kevin!
噢! 凯文!
No, he's not Kevin anymore.
不 他不再是凯文了
Now he is an indestructible, mindless killing machine!
他现在是坚不可摧的盲目屠杀机器!
Just watch this.
来看看吧
And here's the best part!
给你看最厉害的!
I got an army of them!
我有一整团这样的!
Look, look, look!
看看吧!
Soon I will unleash them on the world,
不久后 我就会把他们放出去
and if anyone, anyone tries to stop them...
如果有谁想来阻止他们...
Their city gets eaten!
就把他们的城市都吃掉!
We can do it together.
咱们可以合伙
Together?
合伙?
Together!
合伙!
I have admired your work for years, amigo.
朋友 我一直很欣赏你这些年的工作
Stealing the Moon! Are you kidding?
偷月亮! 那是真的吗?
We would be unstoppable!
无人能阻挡我们!
Men like you, men like me.
像你我这样的人物
We should be ruling the world!
我们就应该统治整个世界!
So, are you in?
你要加入吗?
Uh, yeah, probably.
呃 可能吧
Probably?
可能?
I mean, yes, yes! Of course, yes.
我是想说 加入! 当然加入了
I just have a lot going on right now.
只是我现在正好有些事情
I just need to get some things off my plate
只是我要先去飞碟上拿点东西
before we start taking over the world, that's all.
然后咱们再开始接管整个世界 仅此而已
- Excuse me?  - No, forget it.
- 什么?  - 没事 什么都没说
One hundred percent! I am in!
我加入! 百分百加入!
I think... Do you hear that? I do.
我只是觉得... 听到了吧? 我听到了
That's Agnes calling me from on the surface.
肯定是艾格尼丝在上面叫我呢
Totally in!
绝对加入!
You know what?
你知道吗?
I am not so convinced that he is in.
我不太肯定他会加入呢
Edith, Agnes, come on! Ooh!
伊迪丝 艾格尼丝 过来! 噢!
Oops, sorry.
抱歉
We need to go home now. Where is Margo?
我们现在就要回家了 玛尔戈人呢?
But I didn't get a turn!
但是还没轮到过我玩呢!
Margo!
嘿 玛尔戈!
Come on. We're leaving...
来 我们要走了...
Hey, what's wrong?
怎么了?
I hate boys.
我讨厌男生
Yes. They stink.
恩 男生真讨厌
Uh, sorry. Honey, we got to go.
但是宝贝 咱们得走了
Oops! Sorry.
噢! 不好意思
Hey! Pollito, what's the matter?
嘿! 波立特 怎么了?
Oh, hey, Eduardo!
嘿 爱德华多!
Lucia, I apologize.
我替它道歉 露西
Pollito, he's usually not like this.
波立特他平时不是这样的
The same thing happened the other day with Gru, and...
前几天他见格鲁也是突然大变样...
Oh, well, speaking of Gru, um, have you seen him? I really need to talk to him.
说到格鲁 你有看到他吗? 我有话跟他说
Yes. I think he's somewhere around here.
嗯 他肯定是在这儿
You two are close, no?
你俩关系很不错吧?
Oh, I don't know.
我也说不好
I mean, "close," I wouldn't say we were close.
也不能说是关系不错
Why, did he say we were close? Did he say that?
你为什么说 是他说的我们关系不错?
It's more what he didn't say.
他没说的可多了去了
For instance, he never mentioned
就比如 他从来没提到过
that you were both working for the Anti-Villain League!
你俩都在为反恶联盟工作!
You're coming with me.
你给我过来
Hey!
嘿!
Crikey!
呀!
So, Eduardo's actually El Macho?
所以爱德华多真的是埃尔马乔?
Cool!
哇哦!
No, it is not cool!
一点都不值得哇哦!
Plus, I pretty much knew it was him all along,
另外 我一直都知道是他
so if anyone's cool, it's me!
所以只有我才值得哇哦!
Gru!
嘿 格鲁!
Well, Dr. Nefario.
尼法里奥博士
El Macho's onto you. He knows you're working for the AVL.
埃尔马乔在找你 他知道你在为反恶联盟工作
And he's got your partner.
还抓到了你的拍档
Lucy?
是露西?
That's impossible. She's on her way to Australia!
不可能 她正去往澳大利亚!
Nefario?
尼法里奥 你在哪儿?
Sorry, gotta go!
抱歉 先闪了!
He's got Lucy?
他抓走了露西?
Not for long.
抓不了多久
Come on, we're getting her out of there.
过来 我们去救她出来
What was that?
什么声音?
I don't see anything.
没什么东西呀
Run!
快跑!
My unicorn!
我的独角兽!
Agnes, no!
艾格尼丝 别去!
Come on! Hurry!
来! 快!
What's the matter?
怎么了?
Kevin!
是凯文!
Dr. Nefario! You're back!
尼法里奥博士! 你回来啦!
In the flesh.
就是我
Behold, the antidote.
看 还有解药
Come on. Let's finally put this horrible jelly to some good use.
来 咱们终于要让这些恐怖的果酱派上些用途了
Hey, guys, come on! Stay focused here.
喂 你们 拜托! 都专心点
Curses! Foiled again!
你们这些家伙! 又被打败了吧!
These guys captured me!
这俩家伙逮捕了我!
Run!
跑啊!
Up that tree!
上树!
Hurry! Hurry!
快点! 快点!
Hello, Gru!
你好 格鲁!
Hey hey! Nice work, Dr. Nefario!
嘿! 干得好 尼法里奥博士!
I put an antidote in the jelly.
我在果酱里放了解药
I mean, I'm happy to create an evil army to destroy the world,
我很乐意创造一支坏人军队毁灭整个世界
but nobody messes with my family.
但绝不能伤害我的家人
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你 博士
Now, let's go get the...
就让我们一起去...
Hi!
嗨!
You brought the girls?
你把孩子们也带来了?
Yes!
对啊!
Was that wrong?
有什么问题吗?
What's happening to my minions?
我的仆从都怎么了?
Gru?
是格鲁?
You guys, take care of the rest of the minions.
你们去料理下其他的仆从
I'm going to find Lucy.
我去找露西
Eat jelly, you purple freaks!
吃果酱吧 你们这些小紫人!
It's over, El Macho.
都结束了 埃尔马乔
Now, where is Lucy?
露西在哪里?
Let me show you.
我来给你看看
Oh, hey, Gru!
嘿 格鲁!
Turns out you were right about the whole El Macho thing, huh?
看来你说的埃尔马乔的事儿都对了哈?
Yay!
耶!
One push of this button, and I send that rocket
只要摁下这个键 我就能让火箭
straight into the same volcano where I faked my death.
再次发射到我假死的那个火山口里
Only this time, it's for real.
只不过这次就是真死了
No!
不要!
We could have ruled the world together, Gru!
格鲁 你我本可以携手统治整个世界的!
But now,
但现在
you're gonna die.
你要死了
Mmm, lipstick taser!
口红镭射枪!
Aw, he copied me.
他学我的
I am not afraid of your jelly guns.
我可不怕你们的果酱枪
Oh, this ain't a jelly gun, sunshine.
这可不是果酱枪 这是气枪
Don't worry about me, Gru, I'll be fine.
格鲁 不用担心我 我没事
I have survived lots worse than this.
比这更恶劣的境况下 我都活过来了
Okay, that's not entirely true.
好吧 这句不是实话
I'm actually kind of freaking out up here!
其实我吓得要死了!
Don't worry, I will get you out of this.
别怕 我这就救你出来
I really hate that chicken.
我真的很讨厌这只鸡
Is there a red one? It's usually the red one!
有红的吗? 真的有条红的!
Gru, anytime now!
格鲁 没时间了!
Listen, Lucy, we may not get out of this alive,
露西 听我说 这次我们可能不能活着脱险了
so I need to ask you a question.
所以我一定要问你一个问题
Uh, better make it quick.
最好快点问
If I had asked you out on a date, what would you have said?
如果我邀你出去约会 你会怎么回答?
Are you kidding me?
真的吗?
Yes!
当然是可以!
Jump!
跳!
Lucy!
露西 你在哪儿!
Lucy, where are you?
露西 你在哪儿?
Oh, Lucy!
噢 露西!
Gru!
噢 格鲁!
Sorry! I guess you need your arms to tread water, huh?
抱歉! 忘了你胳膊还得用来划水
They'll be back.
他们还会回来找的
147次约会后
Can I be the first to say, "Ew!"
我要第一个说"呦!"
Okay.
好吧
Excuse me.
抱歉
Um, hi, excuse me.
各位 抱歉
Hi, everybody. I'd like to make some toast.
嗨 各位 我想说些祝酒词
Okay.
好吧
She, um...
她 呃...
She kisses my boo-boos, she braids my hair.
她会亲吻我的小伤口 还会帮我编头发
We love you, mothers, everywhere.
我们爱你 天下所有的妈妈
And my new mom, Lucy, is beyond compare.
还有我的新妈妈 露西 是天下最好的妈妈
To the bride and Gru!
为新娘和格鲁举杯!
Woo-hoo! I'm so happy!
我太开心啦!
不要走开 精彩继续
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 初见 波特妹子 岸
校对: 千欲在纽约
Hey, Bob! Stuart!
嘿 鲍勃! 图尔特!
小黄人电影试镜
No?
不好吗?
Bob!
都是你 鲍勃!
Okay.
好了
Blah.
笨蛋